Joseph Cole-showers

Front-End Developer | UI Designer with a keen eye for detail

Lagos

joseph.c.o216@gmail.com

08119195235

Seasoned and independent Front End Developer with 2 years of experience in blending the art of design with the skill of programming to deliver an immersive and engaging user experience through efficient website development, proactive feature optimization, and relentless debugging.

Work Experience

Frontend Developer

Cerebralhub - Lagos

June 2019 to Present

- Managing access and assigning appropriate permissions to ensure the security of information
- Expand features, refine code, and improve processes, producing smoother operations and enhancing user engagement
- Designed dynamic and browser compatible pages using HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, and Bootstrap

Freelance Frontend Developer

Liveizy - Lagos, Nigeria

August 2020 to November 2020

- Produced stunning visual elements of a home-rental service web application by translating UI/UX design wireframes into code while producing high quality, reusable markup using HTML5, CSS3, and a javascript framework, React.js
- Integrated screens using redux and fetch API
- Adapted to the use of Redux for state management
- Worked with Postman for testing APIs

Freelance Web developer

Bookathon - Lagos

April 2020 to May 2020

- Developed an e-commerce web application to sell books
- Increased web performance

Freelance Web Developer

Crystal Finance Company Limited - Lagos May 2019 to July 2019

- Converted and rebuilt the company's website from Html to WordPress
- Optimized the company's website

Frontend Developer

Bola Adebule & Co - Lagos March 2018 to May 2018

- Developed a real estate website for the company
- Delivered responsive, cross-browser compatible, and accessibility compliant website.

Education

Advanced Diploma In Software Engineering

Aptech Computer Education - Lagos September 2017 to October 2019

Senior Secondary

Engreg High School - Lagos September 2010 to July 2016

Skills

- Html5
- Css
- Bootstrap
- Javascript
- React
- Redux
- SEO
- Adobe XD
- Git
- Wordpress
- · Adobe Photoshop
- Java
- REST Api

Links

http://Linkedin.com/in/joseph-cole-showers-76b06a152/

http://github.com/uncleejay

https://dribbble.com/uncleejay

Certifications and Licenses

Advanced Diploma In Software Engineering

October 2019 to Present

Fundamentals Of Digital Marketing By Google

September 2020 to Present